<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>hackthebox on Micha's Attic</title><link>https://blog.micha.gg/tags/hackthebox/</link><description>Recent content in hackthebox on Micha's Attic</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 00:22:15 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.micha.gg/tags/hackthebox/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>HackTheBox: "Secret" Walkthrough</title><link>https://blog.micha.gg/2022/04/25/hackthebox-secret-walkthrough/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 00:22:15 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.micha.gg/2022/04/25/hackthebox-secret-walkthrough/</guid><description>Foothold As usual, this machine has a landing page - we will find a ZIP file there, which we download, of course. We will immediately notice the .git folder, so let&amp;rsquo;s use git log to inspect what happened there. One of the commit messages sounds interesting:
removed .env for security reasons
Let&amp;rsquo;s inspect the changes introduced by this commit:
-TOKEN_SECRET = gXr67TtoQL8TS... +TOKEN_SECRET = secret This sounds a lot like a real world scenario - left over credentials in a git repository are not unheard of.</description></item><item><title>HackTheBox: "Backdoor" Walkthrough</title><link>https://blog.micha.gg/2022/04/24/hackthebox-backdoor-walkthrough/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2022 19:56:04 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.micha.gg/2022/04/24/hackthebox-backdoor-walkthrough/</guid><description>Introduction The now retired Backdoor machine on HackTheBox is supposed to be an &amp;ldquo;easy&amp;rdquo; machine, so it should be absolutely straight-forward. Let&amp;rsquo;s see!
Foothold On this machine, I started with a directory scan, using the fuzz-Bo0oM.txt list, which usually yields good results - at least on HackTheBox. We&amp;rsquo;ll notice that directory listing is enabled almost everywhere, so we can also explore manually.
In the end, we&amp;rsquo;ll find a pretty standard WordPress installation with a single plugin called &amp;ldquo;ebook-download&amp;rdquo; enabled - for which we will find a LFI vuln pretty quick:</description></item><item><title>HackTheBox: "Shibboleth" Walkthrough</title><link>https://blog.micha.gg/2022/04/22/hackthebox-shibboleth-walkthrough/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 17:36:59 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.micha.gg/2022/04/22/hackthebox-shibboleth-walkthrough/</guid><description>Introduction This is my first walkthrough for a HackTheBox machine. It&amp;rsquo;s not the first machine I&amp;rsquo;ve done, though. But as Shibboleth is now &amp;ldquo;retired&amp;rdquo;, it is allowed to publish walkthroughs. I have decided not to publish any passwords, because that would spoil the fun (and not add anything in terms of learning). I&amp;rsquo;ll rather focus on my chain of thought to go through this challenge.
Foothold The very first scan on every machine I do is a port scan using nmap.</description></item></channel></rss>